Capital Bicycle Club 057
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
- Series 1: Photographs, 1882-1890
  - Portraits – 1880's - Howell Stewart (signed) - (Cabinet Portrait Studio- no negative), 1883 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Portraits – 1880's - Warren Seely (G.W. Davis Studio- no negative), 1883 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Portraits – 1880's - T.F. Schmuder (signed) (Lardner and Co.- no negative), 1885 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Portraits – 1880's - Warren Seely (Bodie Photographic Art Studio- no negative), 1888 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Portraits – 1880's - Rex Smith (signed) (New York Photo Company- no negative), Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Portraits – 1880's - Fred Shaffert (C.M. Bell Artist- no negative), Undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Portraits – 1880's - P.M. Harris (signed) (Pronner Photo- no negative), Undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Portraits – 1880's - E.H. Shipton (Owen Studio- no negative), Undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Portraits – 1880's - Elmer D. Sharretts (Rice Studio- no negative), Undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "On night train from Hagerstown Maryland" (photograph by Max Hansmann - no negative), Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified outing (photographer unknown - negative 7561), Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Star - Evening and Sunday (Rudolph Kauffmann reproductions) - C. Allen (G.W. Davis- negative 6324), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Star - Evening and Sunday (Rudolph Kauffmann reproductions) - Portrait unknown (no negative), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Star - Evening and Sunday (Rudolph Kauffmann reproductions) - C. Allen - L.W. Seely - M. Hansmann - Natural Bridge Tour (photograph by Max Hansmann - negative 14028), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Star - Evening and Sunday (Rudolph Kauffmann reproductions) - Duplicate (photograph by Max Hansmann - negative 14028), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Star - Evening and Sunday (Rudolph Kauffmann reproductions) - Cabin John Bridge (photograph by Max Hansmann - negative 9233), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Star - Evening and Sunday (Rudolph Kauffmann reproductions) - "The Celebrated Cow-Boy Band" (photograph by Max Hansmann - negative 6378), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mounted Star rotogravures - Herbert S. "Bert" Owen's Birthday Run (photograph by Max Hansmann - duplicate- negative 7560), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mounted Star rotogravures - "Capital Bicycle Club in review in front of Arlington Hotel" (photographer unknown - negative 6382), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Series 2: Memorabilia, 1880-1929
  The series consists of scrapbooks and assorted clippings, papers, and programs of the Capital Bicycle Club and it's members from 1880-1929. Box 1 contains the club's official scrapbook from 1880-1890 with Box 2 containing a scrapbook prepared by the D.C. Public Library spanning 1891-1929. Each scrapbook is chronologically arranged by date and contains clippings, prize ribbons, and programs. Both scrapbooks had been assigned a catalog number by the Washington, D.C. Public Library of Wash.Ref.796-606c244r. Of special note is founding member L. Warren Seely's original manuscript for the "Presentation of the Cat", circa 1883. A corresponding transcript is included in the series from The Republic's January 27, 1883 issue. The "Sacred Cat" served as the club's official mascot with the "Procession of the Sacred Cat" held on February 22, 1887. Photographs of the "Procession of the Sacred Cat" can be found in Series I.
  - Capital Bicycle Club Scrapbook, June 1880 - January 1890 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Papers and Clippings of Capital Bicycle Club - Scrapbook organized by Washington Public Library, October 3 1891 – January 31 1929 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Assorted clippings and articles - Newspaper notices of Natural Bridge Tour, 1882 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Assorted clippings and articles - "A Tour to the Natural Bridge" The Wheelman, August 1883 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Assorted clippings and articles - "The Capital and the Capital Club" - The Wheelman, November 1883 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Assorted clippings and articles - "Columbia Bicycle Prize Cup" clipping from The Wheelman, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Assorted clippings and articles - "Presentation of the Cat" transcript from The Republic, January 27 1883 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - L. Warren Seely manuscript "Presentation of the Cat", 1883 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Programs - Eleventh Anniversary Banquet of Capital Bicycle Club, January 31 1890 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Programs - Leap Year Entertainment, February 29 1892 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Assorted papers, 1892-1940 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Assorted papers - Ticket to Annual Excursion to Marshall Hall and Indian Head, July 26 1892 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Assorted papers - Directory, May 6 1907 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Assorted papers - Dinner list, January 15 1929 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Assorted papers - List from Max Hansmann's stationary for "61st Capital Bicycle Club Birthday", January 31 1940 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Assorted papers - Blank membership certificate, Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Exhibit sign with labels, Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Series 3: Official Records, 1881-1911
  The series consists of the official records of the Capital Bicycle Club from 1881-1911. A list of officers for each year is included in the records as well as the club's official meeting minutes as recorded by the Secretary. Box 3 contains copies of the Executive Committee's official correspondence from 1886-1890. Like the scrapbooks in Series II, each record book was assigned the catalog number of Wash.Ref.796-606c244r by the Washington, D.C. Public Library.
  - Capital Bicycle Club Secretary's Record, October 1881 – April 1884 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Capital Bicycle Club Secretary's Record, May 1884 – December 1885 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Capital Bicycle Club Secretary's Record, May 1897-July 1911 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Capital Bicycle Club Secretary's Record, January 1886-October 1895 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Capital Bicycle Club Secretary's Record, January 4, 1886-May 3, 1890 (Box 9, Folder 2)